# **Emmanuel A. Larralde Ortiz**

ealarralde@gmail.com

https://l4rralde.github.io/

https://orcid.org/0009-0009-0938-3603

#### **PROFILE**

Mechatronics Engineer of Instituto Politécnico Nacional and Hardware Engineer at Intel where I have worked with people from many regions of the world. I like challenges, algorithms, digital electronics, and robotics. I also author one IEEE paper.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Hardware Engineer Intel Corporation (February 2023 – today)

- Design Verification of a Novel Branch Prediction Unit of an incoming CPU core.

Technical Graduate Intern Intel Corporation (January 2022 – January 2023)

- Design Verification of the Quick Assist Technology of Intel Xeon Granite Rapids D.

Robotics Software Engineering Intern CIMAT (August 2022 – February 2023)

- Development of autonomous driving software stacks for quadcopters and mobile robots.

**SKILLS** 

# TECHNICAL SKILLS TECHNOLOGIES

PROGRAMMING HARDWARE DESCRIPTION Productivity: Shell scripting, Git & GitHub, Jenkins, Docker.

LANGUAGES LANGUAGES Embedded Systems: Microcontrollers, FPGAs, SBCs, embedded Linux.

Python Verilog/System Verilog Robotics: ROS, Gazebo Sim, Jetson Platforms.

C/C++ VHDL Scientific: Scientific python, MATLAB, wolfram alpha, LaTeX.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Self-taught, Responsibility, Openness to feedback and Teamwork.

# **MAJOR PROJECTS**

**DonkieTown** 2022

A low-cost experimental platform for research on Automated and Connected Vehicles.

- GitHub repository: <a href="https://github.com/L4rralde/DonkieTown">https://github.com/L4rralde/DonkieTown</a>

- IEEE paper: <a href="https://latamt.ieeer9.org/index.php/transactions/article/view/7756">https://latamt.ieeer9.org/index.php/transactions/article/view/7756</a>

PPA 2016 – 2019

An assistance device for caregivers of people with dementia.

- Samsung Awarded this project and invited the team to the Consumer Electronics Show in 2018.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **UPIITA-IPN**

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics Engineering.

August 2017 – December 2022 GPA 94/100

Centro de Investigación en Computación

Domestic exchange program. Graduate courses in Computer Science.

September 2020 – June 2021 GPA 100/100

CECyT 18 "Zacatecas"

Digital Systems Technician.

August 2014 – June 2017

GPA 96/100

**AWARDS** 

First place at Mexican Tournament of Robotics (2023).

Finalist candidate for the International Physics Olympiad (2017).

First place at Samsung's Solve for Tomorrow contest (2018).

Silver Medal in the National Physics Olympiad (2016).